This is Trigun.
Oh, my God.
Target planet on maximum
telefinder range in 5, 4, 3,
2, 1.
Here it comes.
Hey guys, this could be it.
Sure looks promising this
time, don't you think?
I have a good feeling about this.
I think that planet is
going to be our new home.
According to our preliminary
observational data,
it seems to be reasonably similar to home.
Enough with the scientific crap already.
I say we take a chance.
Let's land this puppy.
We've done the cold sleep five times.
If we get frozen one more
time, we'll swivel up.
Knock it off.
You're such a pig, Steve.
It's impossible to
settle here, and besides,
whether we land or not, that's
not a decision for us to make.
It definitely has a habitable environment,
but it has no existing oceans,
and its stratum consists mostly of quartz.
It's not worth waking up the old men.
Hey, Joey, just out of curiosity, what
kind of flowers are on that planet?
Huh?
Uh, well...
Weren't you listening to
what I said before, Rem?
That planet doesn't have...
Hold on.
Why not?
We don't know that yet.
We'll decide once the results
of the minute analysis are in.
For all we know, it just might
have the flowers Rem thinks it has.
If it does, I sure hope
they'll be red flowers.
You're still in here?
Where's Knives?
I was wondering, why
don't they ever wake up?
This ship is too quiet.
It's just you and me and Knives.
And even with the rest of the
crew, there are only seven of us.
All right, Vash.
The day has finally come to tell you what
is written on the outside of this ship.
It says, Project Seeds.
Project Seeds? Yes.
These ships are like seeds that
are filled with our own genes.
Genes from the human race.
They are sent off to discover
and populate an unknown world.
I suppose you could say that we are
the caretakers of all those seeds.
If there's a god in deep space, he
must be laughing at us right now.
Our pitiful struggle for immortality must
look like an impossible quest to him.
Even though it may look shameful
to others, it represents.
For all of us, the desperate human will
to survive, to carry on our species.
When they arrive, a fight
on a new land awaits them.
This ship is their home,
and until it's time,
it's our job to let them sleep in peace.
Rem, is there anything
we can do to help you?
Oh, that's where you are.
So do you want to have lunch in
the usual place, in the rec room?
You really like that song.
It seems to pop into my
head whenever I'm happy.
Do you think it's strange?
No, not really.
It's a nice song.
That's sweet.
Thanks, Knives.
It's weird.
Nothing's actually been moved around.
But every time we come here this
place seems different for some reason?
That's because it's alive!
Can't you feel it?
It has its own rhythm.
You can actually feel the
living part of the plan.
There she goes again thinking about home
So this looks like the world you
and the others keep talking about?
Well sort of but the scenery
at home was actually much more
expansive with a lot more
variety of plants and animals.
I'd like to see that Rem.
We're not just going to see
it We're going to create it.
We'll find a place to create our new home.
And when we get there?
There will be nothing but peaceful
days, with no war and no stealing.
An Eden where people can live
in freedom and harmony, right?
The state of our home, Earth, was so
desperate, we had no choice but to leave.
Mankind could no longer survive there.
The entire population was facing death,
so Project SEES was drafted as
a way to resolve this crisis.
Rem, that's our ship, the
one you told us about.
Judging from the computer data,
it looks to me like mankind is
responsible for damaging the planet.
Right, Captain?
I hate to say it, but it's true.
Our young race believed the land
and resources were unlimited,
which led to gradual destruction.
By the time they realized what
they had done, it was too late.
The planet could no longer take the abuse.
If that's true, why did they come up with
the idea to set this project in motion?
The need to survive. Exactly.
The behavior of clinging to life till the
verge of death is
intrinsic to all organisms.
Survival instincts take over
dismissing shame in order to live.
But is it right to live if it
means such huge sacrifices?
We make the smallest sacrifice
we can think of at the time.
Unlike the other organisms on
the planet, we possess logic.
The knowledge to minimize the sacrifice.
Also, as human beings, we have
the ability to right our wrongs.
Hopefully, we'll learn from our
mistakes and start over in a new home.
As we journey,
we need to take time to
search and think of ways to
make everyone happy without
endangering our environment.
This is no good.
What are you talking about?
I'm not cut out to be an educator.
What was I thinking, Rem?
I can only teach them
how to use the computer.
I've never been a father.
I don't know the first
thing about raising kids.
That goes double for me.
No, I'm serious.
You're teaching them all sorts
of things, like emotions,
how to be kind to others,
and the value of the future.
I'm not that great, Joey, really.
I just play with them, that's all.
It's no big deal.
Yeah, I guess we just have a
different way of looking at things.
You know, I was thinking, why do
you suppose they came here anyway?
Because they're angels. Angels?
Perhaps we should pay
more attention to them.
Bash and Knives could be angels God
sent to point us in the right direction.
They may even guide us through our dream.
Hey, Rem here?
No, she's with the kids in the rec room.
Like there isn't a care in the world.
Apparently she doesn't realize we
still have three plants left to adjust.
Oh yes, I meant to tell you.
The two little guys took care
of those while you were napping.
What?
Tell me you're kidding, Rowan.
I'm fast, but that's still
a two-day job for me.
What's with them?
It's nothing to be surprised about.
Their IQ is way above ours.
Don't take it so personally.
You should be glad
they're willing to help.
Maybe they're better suited
for brain work than you, Steve.
You need to lighten up
on those kids a little.
Cut the crap!
Do you really want the ship left
in the hands of those monsters?
Just look at how big
they grew in one year.
It isn't normal.
Those kids are monsters, I tell you.
Monsters!
Vash. Vash.
Hey, you're crying again.
What's the matter?
It's Steve.
He says that we're not human.
He hates me.
I know it's hard to understand, but to
these people, we're just uninvited guests.
We only need to be patient for a
little while until they accept us.
But Rem said that we could stay here.
Do you think she feels that way?
Remember what Joey said?
We have to make the smallest
sacrifice we can think of at the time.
If we can do that, we
can get through anything.
Hey, Vash, do you know
why plants can't talk?
Rem said it's because
they're stronger than we are.
She said they're so strong, they
concentrate all their energy on living,
so they don't need to use words.
Yeah, they're strong,
but we eat their fruit.
We have to eat their fruit to live.
Do you think I'll be eating someday?
No, Knives, definitely not.
At least according to Rem.
Don't you remember?
She said they're making
a different kind of Eden.
Knives!
What the hell are you doing in here?
This place is off limits to your kind.
You got that, monster?
So then why am I here?
Don't!
There's got to be a reason.
Knives, it won't be much longer.
Take your time.
This is turning into quite a trim.
I never noticed before,
but you're really handsome.
Really?
You think so, Rem?
Hey!
I have an idea, handsome.
It's sticking up.
I think it's great.
It really suits you, Vash.
and it reminds me of him.
Who?
Someone I loved very much back home.
So where is he now, Rem?
He is in the land of angels, heaven.
He was my emotional support.
Thanks to him, I was able to face
my mistakes without judgment.
I learned to make them right again.
Then I lost him and realized
that I would have to do it alone.
But I wasn't afraid to
make mistakes anymore.
I believed I could point myself in the
right direction without looking back.
That is exactly why I got on this ship,
so I could enter the future as I am.
Rem, are you sad?
Well, just a little.
You know, you have me.
I won't leave you alone.
I promise I won't, because
I really love you, Rem.
You're such a baby.
But thank you, Vash.
Anyway, we're done.
Shall we switch now?
Knives!
It's all wrong!
Hey, somehow I knew you'd be in here.
What happened?
Just a small change of heart, that's all.
Besides, if we stay the same,
there's no individuality.
That's a wonderful
haircut, Knives! Thank you.
As strange as it may sound,
I actually feel refreshed.
You know, you look very intellectual.
Why, you look like a
regular little philosopher.
What do I look like?
A mama's boy. That's me.
Huh?
I'm amazed you can stomach eating at the
same table with those little monsters.
Steve, I think you've had one too many.
No, I haven't, baby.
Hey, Steve, come on.
Don't you have some work you
still have to do someplace else?
Oh, shut up, Poindexter.
I can always do that later.
You're a disgrace.
Huh?
Now,
is that any way for a
grown man like you to
behave in the presence
of innocent children?
He sure has been acting crazy lately.
It's because he's afraid.
Who does he think he is draping
himself all over Mary like that?
Those two are such a pain.
But then again, I suppose just
one would be rather boring.
Oh
That was the easiest way to stop him.
You wanted to save the butterfly, right?
I Didn't want to kill the spider.
I wanted to save them both
What are you talking about
unless the spider caught
the butterfly it would
die of starvation anyway?
You can't save both.
Don't you know that?
It's not right to make
that choice so easily.
Both of them are living creatures knives,
so you should but I'm not
wrong about this realm!
If you just keep saving the
butterflies the spiders will die?
Yes, but...
Wanting to save both is
just a naive contradiction.
And what would you have rather had us do?
Just stand and think about it?
In the meantime, while we do that,
the spider eats the butterfly.
What's wrong with you, Nye?
Don't you understand?
I wanted to save both of them, you idiot!
You don't make any sense, Bash.
I don't think so, Knives!
You're the one who doesn't make any sense!
According to interplanetary
law, Steve is relieved of duty.
He will be detained in the freezer.
Furthermore, upon the
completion of our mission,
he will be released from
detention to stand trial.
That is all.
All I did was get a little drunk!
Why can't you believe what I'm saying?
We haven't heard his side yet.
You're not being fair to him.
I saw him go into Mary's room,
and I find that unacceptable.
Hey, wait!
I didn't do anything!
We still have time to discuss this.
In order for us to function
as a group, we need law.
It protects all of us from harm.
The entire team must understand this.
But maybe it wouldn't hurt to hear his
side of the story before we freeze him!
Rem, he raped me.
No!
I didn't do it!
Rem, why can't everyone just
get along with each other?
I suppose it's because people have
many different ways of thinking.
But even if we do make mistakes,
we have the ability to do something about
it and make better choices the next time.
And if you keep your vision
clear, you will see the future.
What happens in our future
is our own responsibility.
Marry you?
You.
Come on, you must be teasing.
As soon as we're finished here,
I'd like you to come to the bridge.
The analysis should be in
in just a little while.
I made sure that Steve
will never wake up again.
I readjusted the freezer.
I didn't mean for us to kill him!
I guess now that means we're partners.
Joey!
What's wrong, Rem?
The A-12 monitors.
Somebody disconnected them.
It's her own fault. I had no choice.
I helped her and then she betrayed me.
I was only trying to
protect her from Steve.
Rowan, please don't.
She even told me she loved me.
There's simply no excuse.
Rem, you do understand me.
Oh, I see now.
It had to be him.
Because of him, Mary had to die.
It was his fault.
What are you talking about, Rowan?
Please put the gun down!
Rem, what's happening? Rem! Rem!
He can't get away with it, that monster.
I have to shoot him.
Now get out of the way, Rem!
No one has the right to
take the life of another.
You don't want to kill him.
Now put it down.
It's not too late.
Stay! Stay! Stay!
Rowan, what are you doing?
Something's broken inside me.
I'm done.
I can't seem to stop.
It's all right, Rowan.
Rem, get out of there!
Rem!
It's not too late to start over.
Here.
Please stay back, Rem.
Don't make me shoot you!
No, Rowan, nooo!
Why did you do that, Joey?
If I hadn't, he would have shot you.
I'm sorry, there was no other way.
I knew Rowan, he wouldn't shoot me.
Please understand, I couldn't
see that from the monitors.
I had to decide quickly. If I hadn't...
Rowan...
Mary...
Joey, I agree with you.
I think you did exactly the right thing.
Rowan went crazy.
That's all you could do.
That's what I thought.
But what if Rem was right?
Perhaps he wasn't going to shoot her.
If that's true, what I did
was a horrible mistake.
You're just a human,
like the rest of them.
I know my choice is the right one.
Altering ship's course program.
What is it?
We're changing direction.
Our course has been re-entered.
What?
Someone is sending orders
to all of the ships.
All systems are now operating
on auto-lock mode. Oh, my God.
At this rate, the ships are
going to crash on that planet.
Apparently, Rowan had started
up the orbital program.
We have to evacuate.
Where's Joey?
He told me to get us to the escape pods.
He said he'd try to save the ships.
But what about all the
sleeping people on board?
We can't worry about that.
We've got to get out of here.
Rem, come on.
We have to go to the pods.
Warning. Warning.
This ship is about to
enter the atmosphere.
Please proceed to the escape pods.
Come on.
You've got to hurry, Rem.
A fight on a new land awaits them.
We're not going to see it,
we're going to create it.
And if you keep your vision
clear, you will see the future.
What happens in our future
is our own responsibility.
Ram, what's the matter?
Alex, help me. Give me strength.
You two go on ahead.
I don't understand what you mean.
Why?
I can't leave Joey here by himself.
And I have to try to find
a way to save the others.
But the program is already running.
You've got to come with us, Ram.
Please don't leave us!
I'm sorry, Vash.
If Alex were still alive, I believe in
my heart that he would do the same thing.
Vash, take care of knives!
Don't worry, Vash.
No, Rem!
No, you can't leave!
Please come back, Rem!
I'll never understand humans.
They're a total waste of life.
To think they'd actually sacrifice themselves
out of foolish sentiment for others.
It's incomprehensible.
I thought I'd let her live only
because you were so attached to her.
But now I see how truly
imperfect she really was.
It's a good thing she died.
Don't say that!
Their immigration is out of the question.
That'd be like spreading pathogenic
organisms across our healthy universe.
You're saying you planned
this? That's right.
But don't worry, you and I will be fine.
I made sure the planned ship will survive.
After all, we need that
to create our new home.
Now, won't we, my dearest brother?
Only ships carrying the humans will crash.
Ah!
Bring them back!
Bring them back, you bastard!
All ships now commencing
orbital correction.
Reverse thrusters.
That bitch actually did it.
I'm sorry, Rem.
Vash, take care of knives.
Trust me, Rem.
I will...
take care of him.
Thank
you
so
much for watching.
Aishita o mitsumete Mary
shining down upon us from the
skies, stained red with blood.
And let us remember his name, his legend.
To do so, you only need to look up.
Like it or not, his legend is
chiseled into the fifth moon,
a permanent etching from a terrible past.
The legend of Vash the
Stampede, chiseled forever.
And then the time comes, you
only need to tell of the tracks,
which lead to the future.